# **NEVEN RECCHIA**

■ nevenrecchia@gmail.com (781) 738-2776 Norwell, MA in nevenrecchia NRec22

I am a recent graduate from the College of Information and Computer Sciences at UMass Amherst and a recent new hire at Liberty Mutual Insurance IT. My wide ranged interests of different fields within computer science allow me to be versatile and open to new techniques and solutions. I am currently pursuing to further develop my skills and gain further experience in the corporate environment.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Massachusetts Amherst: Commonwealth Honors College**

B.S. Computer Science 2017

GPA: 3.52

Multidisciplinary Honors Undergraduate with Distinction & Dean's List Awards

Honors Thesis: "Honor Through Self-Sacrifice: Nonconformist Behavior In Samurai Conflicts"

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Data Management, Information Systems, Web Programming, Algorithms, OS

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Liberty Mutual Insurance**

TechStart Program Associate · Boston, MA

September 2017 - Present

- Participated in numerous technical boot camps covering Agile, Spring Boot Web Development, Behavior Driven Development, and Web Security
- · Completed LibertyHacks Challenge assignment with a web application designed to aid IT security teams track security risk.
- · Currently working with the USCM IT DevOps Chef Team on the development and deployment of Chef cookbooks for NGINX

#### U.S. Consumer Markets IT Internship · Dover, NH

June 2016 - August 2016

- · Provided internal support for tools and suites including Jenkins, HP Application Lifecycle Management, and IBM Ration Team Concert.
- Contributed to the refactoring of a permissions request handler automation script built in Talend.
- Handled outage incidents and administrated access rights.

# **UMass Amherst Information Technology**

Computer Classrooms Technical & Staffroom Consultant · Amherst, MA

September 2013 - May 2017

- Oversaw and maintained daily operations from the staffroom.
- · Provided assistance to students and professors in computer classrooms around campus.
- Repaired and troubleshoot computers, printers, scanners, and other devices around campus.

### **SKILLS**

Languages: Java, JavaScript, Scala, SQL, Python, HTML, CSS, Ruby, C

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Frameworks, Platforms, Tools: Git, Node.js, AWS EC2, Chef, D3.js, NGINX, VirtualBox, Eclipse, Datagrip

#### **PROJECTS**

#### LibertyHacks Challenge: Personalized Security Information Portal

- A web application to help IT Security track and present security risk of platforms and components so that IT engineers can make more informed design decisions.
- · Designed with MongoDB, Node.js, and Express to use data hosted by NIST (National Institute of Standards and Technology).
- Users select desired tools, frameworks, or technologies and receive a generated report with aggregated risk assessments.

## **VAST Challenge 2015 Dataset Visualization Project**

- Interactive data visualization project that uses a sample movement tracking data from visitors at a fictional theme park over the course of a weekend.
- Built with D3.js, Dc.js, and Crossfilter libraries.
- Explores relationships between the guest activities, the types of rides they prefer, the park areas they visit, and how these trend over time.

#### **U-Food Web Application**

- Developed a web application aimed to provide updates and reviews of UMass Dining to the students.
- Built with Node.js, Handlebars, and Express, using a PostgreSQL database.
- · Designed for easy user functionality and contains a review system for each dining commons page.

## **EXTRACURRICULAR**

## **UMass Association of Computing Machinery Chapter**

January 2015 - May 2017

Active member in meetings, presentations, and tech talks on varied topics across the computer science industry.

# Hackers of UMass Club January 2015 - May 2017

Active member of student run group participating in local hackathons and programming workshops.

# **Boy Scouts of America: Troop 66 Norwell**

July 2013